Saurabh Kavhar

Frontend Web Developer

Knowledgeable Front End Developer adept at creating successful websites that meet customer needs. Demonstrated talent for front back-end web development to optimize online presence. Seasoned expert in languages such as HTML, CSS and Bootstrap as well as scripting language JavaScript



EDUCATION

2019

Bachelor of Information Technology Prince College (Nov 2008 - Sept 2013)

2020

Diploma in Web Designing Pune



WORK EXPERIENCE

2021

Freelancer

Brand Mitra (Jan 2022 - Mar 2022)

- Developed a HMS called Swasthya. Worked on the Frontend designing part with the help of Bootstrap.
- Design pattern MVC

2021

Frontend Developer

Digital King (Sep 2020 - Dec 2021)

- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Managed full-cycle design tasks, handling phases from conception to completion while maintaining guidelines throughout.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.

2020

Web Designer Intern

Digital King (Mar 2020 - Aug2020)

- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery languages.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript.
- Provided front-end website development using WordPress, Hubspot and other editing software
- · Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Created Web Design as per the client requirement.
- Performed Wireframing, Prototyping and various activities involved in Ui /Ux designing process.

Contact

9730095776



skavharlll@gmail.com



dribbble.com/starboy_13



linkedin.com/in/skavhar/



saurabhkavhar.com



SKILLS

Frontend	Web Design	Personal
HTML5	Figma	Persistent
CSS3	Adobe Xd	Communication
Javascript	Adobe Illustrator	Creativeness
Bootstrap, Tailwind	Adobe Photoshop	Critical Thinking
React	Canva	Decision Making
AJAX	Google Web Designer	Team Work



PROJECTS

Accident Detection System (BE final project/Major project)

We had developed an Accident detection device which had multiple sensors to acquire data. These sensors were connected to our device using a bluetooth module. On the basis of this data, predictions were made if it's accident or not. If accident has occurs then position of user and other accident details will be sent to family as well as near police station and Hospitals

Library Management System (BE 3rd year/Minor project)

I have created an automated library system for our colleague. Where students can search, request or return books to the library using this system.Backend language was Core java ,IDE used was netbeans and database was MySql.



HOBBIES AND INTEREST

Aside from learning new things and creativity, I am also interested in playing snooker, Board games, riding bikes, and exploring new places.

I am fluent in English, Hindi, and Marathi.



CERTIFICATIONS

- 1. React Js Udemy course completion.
- 2. Full stack Web Development online course from Udemy.